I added the code that we were just looking at into our app.
このアプリにコードを 追加しました
It says View orderSummaryTextView = findViewById,
“View orderSummaryTextView = findViewById” とあり
then we pass in the resource ID for the order_summary_text_view.
“order_summary_text_view” の リソース ID を渡します
But this causes an error in Android Studio on the next line.
しかし次の行で エラーがあります
It says it cannot resolve the method setText.
“Cannot resolve the method setText” と
If I add another line of code here,
出ます 行を追加すると
I can show you the types of methods that are valid on this variable.
この変数で有効な メソッド型が出ます
So, we just created the orderSummaryTextView variable here,
“orderSummaryTextView” の 変数をここに作成します
and it's a TypeView, and so
TypeView なので
on the next line, we should be able to call methods on it.
次の行でメソッドを 呼び出せるはずです
But if you look at the autocomplete suggestions,
しかし自動入力の 候補を見ると
these methods are actually View methods.
これらは全て View メソッドです
There's no TextView specific methods.
TextView 用のものは ありません
For example, there's no setText method.
例えば setText メソッドは ないので
That's why we get an error down here when we try to call setText.
エラーになり setText を呼び出しても
You also can't set text size, or set text color, or any of those.
テキストのサイズや 色の設定は不可です
So where are all those methods?
ではそのメソッドは どこでしょう
Well, the thing is that a TextView is a more specific type of View.
TextView は特定的な View の型なので
So if we want to call TextView methods
このオブジェクトで TextView メソッドを
on this object we need to make sure that this is a TextView object.
呼び出すには TextView オブジェクトであること
Okay. Now the variable is a TextView object.
今度は変数が TextView オブジェクトです
But then I get another error that says incompatible types, because a TextView
しかし普通のビューを 探しているにも拘らず
is required on the right hand side, but we're finding just a regular view.
右側に TextView が必要な為 “型が合わない” と出ました
That's because the findViewById method returns a View.
findViewById メソッドが View に戻るからです
So how do we reconcile this?
ではどうやって 一致させるのでしょう
Well, since TextView is a more specific type of View or put another way,
TextView が View の 特定の型ということは
a TextView is a subclass of view, we can actually use something called casting.
TextView は View のサブクラス つまりキャストが使えます
Casting in Java means that we can take the View returned by this method and
Java でのキャストは このメソッドで
actually treat it as a TextView.
戻った View を TextView として扱えるので
So now this right hand side is actually a TextView object, and
右側は TextView オブジェクトで
then we can store it inside this orderSummaryTextView variable.
orderSummaryTextView に 保存できます
I know that this must be really overwhelming because I just mentioned
新しいことを 多く学んだばかりで
a ton of new concepts.
参ってしまいますよね
Let me try to explain again.
再度説明します
The findViewById method turns an object of type View.
findViewById メソッドは View 型のオブジェクトになり
By writing this notation,
この様に丸括弧して
parentheses with the desired object data type in the middle of it.
真ん中にオブジェクトの データ型を入力します
We're casting this View into a TextView.
View を TextView の 中にキャストします
So the whole expression here evaluates to a TextView object.
そして TextView オブジェクトを 全ての宣言が評価します
Then, we can store that in the variable, on the left-hand side,
すると左側に “TextView” 型を持つ
which is orderSummary TextView, and it has a type TextView.
変数 “orderSummary TextView” が保存できます
Now, on subsequent lines, we can call TextView methods on this object.
下の行では TextView メソッドが呼び出せます
Do you see now how all the text methods are showing up here?
全てのテキストメソッドが 表示されましたね
setAllCaps, setTextSize, and more.
setAllCaps や setTextSize 等があります
So I can just erase this now, because setText should work,
setText で大丈夫なはず なのでこれは消します
and there's no more errors.
エラーが なくなりました
So if we want to be able to call TextView methods,
TextView メソッドの 使用を可能にするには
we need to have a TextView object.
TextView オブジェクトが 必要になります
In order to have a TextView object, We need to call findViewById,
TextView オブジェクトには findViewById が必要なので
and then cast this View object into a TextView.
View オブジェクトを TextView にキャストします
The reason why casting works is because
キャストが 有効な理由は
this View here in the view hierarchy is actually a TextView.
ビュー階層の View が TextView だからです
If we we try to cast it into something like a radio button, that wouldn't work,
ラジオボタン等には キャストできません
because the orderSummaryTextView is actually a TextView, so
“order_summary_text_view” がTextView だからです
we have to cast it into the appropriate type.
キャストは適切な型に 対して行いましょう
Similarly, in the displayQuantity method, we're calling findViewById and
displayQuantity メソッドも同様 “findViewById” を呼び出して
we're passing in this resource ID for the quantity TextView.
数量 TextView の リソース ID を渡します
This returns a View, and we cast it into a TextView, and
これが View を戻すので “TextView” にキャストします
we can store that inside this variable called quantityTextView.
すると変数 quantityTextView に 保存できます
This variable has type TextView, and so,
この変数には TextView 型があり
on subsequent lines, we can TextView methods on it, like setText.
下の行で “setText” 等 TextView が使えます
Here's the updated MainActivity code using casting.
キャストを使った最新の MainActivity コードです
We can cast these Views into TextViews so that we can store them in variables
TextViews に Views を キャストして TextViews 型の
that have type TextView so in this list of MainActivity variables,
変数に保存ができるので MainActivity のリストでは
now quantityTextView and orderSummaryTextView are type TextView.
“quantityTextView” と “orderSummaryTextView” は
We can call TextView methods on these,
TextView 型です—これを TextView メソッドと呼び
and we're not just limited to treating them as Views.
Views として扱う だけでなく
And now we can call TextView specific methods on these variables.
この変数では TextView に 特化したメソッドもあります
For example we can call setText on the orderSummaryTextView,
orderSummaryTextView で setText が呼び出せます
and we can call setText on the quantityTextView.
また quantityTextView でも setText が呼び出せます
As you can see,
見ての通り
you have to be careful about what data types are being used where.
どのデータ型をどこで 使うか注意が必要です
So far, when we've called methods, we haven't worried about the return value,
メソッドを呼び出す時は setText メソッドに
because the setText method actually has no return value.
戻り値がなかったため 気にしませんでした
Same with the imageView.setImageResource method.
imageView.setImageResource メソッドでも同様です
This has no return value.
これも戻り値が ありません
But other methods can have return values.
しかし他のメソッドは どうでしょう
For example, in the TextView class we have a getTextSize method.
例えば TextView クラスの getTextSize メソッドは
This returns an integer, so
戻り値が 整数型です
we can store the result of this method in a variable called size of type int.
戻り値は int 型の 変数 “size” で保存できます
Here's another method that has a return value.
戻り値のあるメソッドの もう一つの例です
In the Button class you can call the getHeight method,
Button クラスで getHeight メソッドを
and this returns an integer value, so you can store it inside a variable.
呼び出すと整数値を 戻して変数に保存が可能
If you tried to store this result inside a string, for example,
もしストリングの中で 結果の保存を試みると
you would get an error, because this method returns an integer.
メソッドが整数を戻すので エラーになります
In order to know what type of data needs to be passed into a method and what data
メソッドに渡すべき データ型やメソッドから
type gets returned back from a method, you should check the documentation.
戻るデータ型を知るには Documentation を確認します
And for example, in the TextView class,
例えば TextView クラスでは
if you call any of these methods, it returns a value of type int.
これらを呼び出す場合 int 型の値を戻します
The return value data type is in the left-hand column here.
戻り値のデータ型は 左の列にあります
For other methods, you might get void as a return value, or booleans,
他にも戻り値には “void” や “booleans” もあります
which we haven't learned about yet, or floats or longs and etc.
まだ習っていませんが “floats” “longs” 等もあります
This documentation page also shows what are the expected data types for
この Documentation は 各メソッドに入力する
the inputs for each method.
データ型も示します
For example, the setTextColor method requires an integer as input and
setTextColor メソッドなら 整数の入力が必要です
the return value is void, so there's no return value.
戻り値は “void” なので 戻り値はありません
So check the documentation to know what data types are expected.
Android Studio でデータ型の 不一致のエラーが
Otherwise, you'll get errors in Android Studio saying that
出ないようデータ型を Documentation で
the data types don't match.
確認しましょう
Now it's your turn to practice.
それでは練習です
Below are four different code examples.
これらは４つの異なる コード例です
Some of the code may contain errors relating to data types not matching.
いくつかにはデータ型の 不一致のエラーがあります
If you find an error,
見つけたら
describe how you're supposed to fix it by writing it in the boxes provided.
修正方法をボックスに 書いて下さい
Otherwise, you can just write No error if the code is perfectly fine.
間違いがなければ “No error” と書いて下さい
This is going to be challenging quiz because we just covered
多くの新しいコードを 勉強したばかりなので
a lot of concepts, and this code is still pretty new to you.
少々難しいかも 知れません
Take your time and check the documentation for these methods.
Documentation を確認しながら じっくりと解いて下さい
Make sure that the inputs and the return values are correct and
入力内容と戻り値が正しいか 必ず確認しましょう
that, if we're declaring variables, that we have the correct data types here.
変数の宣言でデータ型が 正しいか確認しましょう
Also, look up the documentation for
また正しくメソッドを
these method calls to make sure that we're using the methods correctly.
使っているか Documentation で 確認しましょう